<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Loudberry</title>
  <link href="http://daegalus.github.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://daegalus.github.com//"/>
  <updated>2011-09-14T01:10:40-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://daegalus.github.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name>Yulian Kuncheff</name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Installing Windows 8 On A Macbook Air</title>
    <link href="http://daegalus.github.com//blog/2011/09/14/installing-windows-8-on-a-macbook-air/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://daegalus.github.com//blog/2011/09/14/installing-windows-8-on-a-macbook-air</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I spent a good portion of my night trying to get Windows 8 to work on the Macbook Air. In the end I finally succeeded and it works amazingly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I will give quick and dirty instructions, they won't be too detailed, but hopefully those that are doing this are knowledgable enough to figure this out part way. You will need 2 USBs for this process, and access to your OSX partition, along with patience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recommend premtively downloading the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brentnorris.net/orca.msi&quot;&gt;Orca MSI editor&lt;/a&gt; and also making a Bootcamp Driver USB for all the drivers (the driver USB is required.) You will also need an archiver. Put all of these on 1 USB , just make sure you put the non Bootcamp stuff on there AFTER you make it a Bootcamp Driver USB from OSX.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In OSX, make a Bootcamp Driver USB and set it aside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From another Windows install on another computer, or another partition, make a Bootable USB Installer for Windows 8. You can use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://images2.store.microsoft.com/prod/clustera/framework/w7udt/1.0/en-us/Windows7-USB-DVD-tool.exe&quot;&gt;Windows 7 DVD/USB Download Tool&lt;/a&gt; or any other means.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run the Windows Installer from USB like you would do for Windows 7. The install process is almost 100% identical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once it reboots, make sure that after you select Windows in the Mac bootloader, not to touch your keyboard. I have had it lockup a few times and had to do fresh installs. Just let it do its thing until you hit the License agreement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you will notice that the Screen is cut in half, and there are 2 copies of hte top half of your screen. This sadly is due to a buggy Windows 8 Intel HD 3000 driver. You will have to click randomly on the bottom of the screen till it switches to the next screen. This is pretty annoying. I tried tabbing through this, but I have no clue if there is a &quot;Checkbox&quot; or not down there. I just finally got it to move on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This problem will persist through a while, so you will have to use your knowledge of tabbing and windows shortcuts to move around, and a bit of mental image of how things can/are laid out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you get it all setup and boot in, you should be able to hit the Explorer shortcut or the Desktop tile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once there plugin the USB or however you are storing the Orca editor, and install it onto the system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once done, plug in the USB with Bootcamp Drivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open Orca, and browse into the &quot;F:\WindowsSupport\Drivers\Apple&quot; (Driver letter doesn't matter, I am just picking something). Select the BootCamp or Bootcamp64.msi and open it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Tables column, scrolldown until you see &quot;LaunchConditions&quot; and select it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look for a row that says &quot;VersionNT=601&quot; right-click it and drop row. If you have problems with it not seeing Mac partitions or not figuring out the system model properly, delete the last line with &quot;SYSTEMMODELNAME&quot; in the line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now go to the folder, and run the MSI file directly. Wait till it does all its installs and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now go back up one folder to WindowsSupport\Drivers and Go into every folder, and install all the drivers manually. If you know exactly what drivers you need, instll only those, otherwise just go through all of them, and ignore any &quot;Errors&quot; about missing hardware, or other info. I know for Macbook Airs, you can skip the IDT Sigmatel driver. Also for the time being, skip the Intel945, Intel965 install and, IntelHDGraphicsSetup. Others should install fine. If they say Unsupported OS, defer them till later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once that is all done, take your favorite Archiver (WinRar, 7zip, whatever), and extract the IntelHDGraphicsSetup exe. It is a self extracting archive, so it just has the installer inside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once extracted go to the &quot;Graphics&quot; folder, and open the file &quot;2430-64p.ini&quot; and scroll down until you see [IntelGfx.NTamd64.6.2] (yours might be a bit different if you are doing this on 32-bit). Under it there is a comment about &quot;no install on Win8&quot;. Directly below that you should see the one for 6.0 (win7/vista) copy all the lines below it, and paste them under the 6.2 category. Save it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go up a folder, and run the Setup.exe. The this should being installing the Driver. If it asks you about downgrading the version, hit yes. When the popup saying it is unsigned, and so on pops up continue. Your display should fix up almost right away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From here, do the same process (roughly) to get the other Intel packages that you think you might need to install.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;During this process, reboot at every step that you are asked to restart on. Also, you will be doing this with only half your screen. So you will have to do window resizing and moving, launching things from memory, or just guessing positions of things to get things working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should hopefully help some of you figure it out. This process can be used for any mac, and your mileage will vary. Some systems might not have to mess around with the screen stuff because it will just work (Nvidia/ATI video cards, I cant say for sure though). You will still have to do the rest for proper drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Using Agile for Personal Project Management</title>
    <link href="http://daegalus.github.com//blog/2011/09/04/using-agile-for-personal-project-management/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-04T00:53:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://daegalus.github.com//blog/2011/09/04/using-agile-for-personal-project-management</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My internship experience at EA this last summer has given me a new experience with Agile/Scrum development. Because it was incorporated so well into the development process of what I was working on, it really made a great impression to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I am no longer working there and come back to my own projects, I have found I have way too many ideas, way too many projects, and I was all over the place with them. This eventually makes me complacent and I never get anything finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided that I would incorporate Agile into my personal development flow. I recently bought most of the Atlassian software, and seeing as how it was for personal use, $10 per product wasn't that expensive. So I got JIRA, Bamboo, Greenhopper, etc. And set them all up. The tool that I was looking forward to using the most was Greenhopper, their Agile management tool. My plan was to setup all my projects, and begin managing my time in sprints and stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about a month of doing this, I have found that it works tremendously well. I have basic stories for getting bits and pieces done, and I gave myself 2 weeks to do them. 1.5 for coding, .5 for testing. Reason I gave myself such a big sprint is because I have to juggle college classes along with all of this, and giving myself plenty of time to knockout a few functions or classes works well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I am mostly using this as a method to get organized. If I stick to it, it works. I am getting a lot of work done on my projects, and I can monitor how much I am completing and how quickly. In a lot of cases, I had extra time, so I started work on other features, and even knocked out 2-3 stories in a sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this seems like an overly complex setup for a single developer, to-do lists, and just random jots never work for me and I have completed more coding towards my projects in the last month, than I have in the 6 months prior to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are having trouble getting stuff done, find a free Agile management tool, or buy a cheap one, and get yourself setup and organized through it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Node.js Is Interesting Stuff</title>
    <link href="http://daegalus.github.com//blog/2011/09/04/node-dot-js-is-interesting-stuff/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-04T00:13:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://daegalus.github.com//blog/2011/09/04/node-dot-js-is-interesting-stuff</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have recently jumped onto the Node.js bandwagon after finally deciding to see what it was all about. And after a few test scripts, I think I know what I am going to be using for my future REST/Web projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my limited amount of usage, its fast. Responses to my calls came back quickly and everything worked great with little overhead on my linux box. Not to mention my linux box is an old emachines laptop with 2gigs of ram, and an old AMD 64bit processor. I've setup quite a bit on it, and it finally crapped out when I started installing a slew of Atlassian products on it. Those really bogged it down and I could barely get anything to load decently. Plus it took 10-15 seconds for it to send a response back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously this isn't an all too serious metric, since it is an old machine, but I am looking forward to writing as much as possible with Node.js for the services and games I plan to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention I enjoy using MongoDB and its Geospatial features. MongoDB works extremely well with Node.js, so it is a great combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first I thought all this Node.js stuff was something dumb, because I am not a fan of Javascript and all this AJAX craze that has been going on for the last few years. But I can say that after playing around with Node.js for a while, it is fun to code for, and it works well. If you haven't given it a try, be sure to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Blogging, I can never get into this</title>
    <link href="http://daegalus.github.com//blog/2011/09/03/blogging/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-03T01:35:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://daegalus.github.com//blog/2011/09/03/blogging</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, I am going to take a swing at blogging once more. I have tried a few times, but I can just never get it right. Hopefully this time around I can be active about it and maybe write something useful. If not, I can just put another grave in my &quot;Things that just don't work for me&quot; box alongside Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will most likely stick to technological/programming articles here, but there might be a few occasional ones that are just completely unrelated, but those will be filed under the appropriate tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also a gamer, so most of my other stuff might be related to gaming or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this works out better than last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Just a test of syntax highlighted code on some Node.js stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;``` js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var http = require('http');
var server = http.createServer(function(req,res) {
  res.writeHead(200);
  res.end('Hello World');
});
server.listen(8124);

var hello = require('./hello');
hello.world();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;```&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
